# RYAN ARNOLD

# Windermere, FL 34786 | (845) 475-4377 | ryannarnoldd@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

## **Professional Summary**

Graduated high school in June 2020 with an intense passion for software and web development. Over the next two years, acquired a bachelor's degree in computer science. Highly motivated, goal-oriented, and energetic self-starter that works well with others. Able to adapt quickly and effectively to changes in academic and working environments. Community and environmentally minded, passionate for nonprofit activities in these two arenas. Moved to Florida seeking to use problem-solving and computer science skills to shape a brighter future.

### **Education**

**Bachelor of Science**: Computer Science

05/2022

SUNY New Paltz - New Paltz, NY

- Completed year with GPA of 3.87
- Dean's List for Academic Achievement
- Completed bachelor's degree within two years of exiting High School

Associate of Science: Computer Science

12/2020

SUNY Dutchess College - Poughkeepsie, NY

- Graduated with GPA of 3.92
- President's List for Academic Achievement
- Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society

# **Projects**

#### FaithTasks Mobile Web Application

01/2023 to Present

- Personal web application to encourage others to carry out tasks involving their faith
- Displays daily tasks for users to do and share with others
- Uses Local Storage system to keep track of user's completed tasks and notes
- Languages: HTML, SCSS, JavaScript, and JSON
- Framework: React

#### User Management and Submission Engine Website: Projects (CPS 485)

05/2022

- Distinguished capstone presentation, presented at university
- Developed website to aid students to learn Operating Systems concepts
- Specialization on the User Management and Submission Engine
- Managed local files and form data collection in Database Management
- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and MySQL
- Frameworks: Bootstrap and Bulma

- Used to dynamically track workouts and nutrition, view/discover friends, and view/share posts
- Designed and implemented features such as login, logout, and access restriction to features
- Languages: HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Frameworks: Bulma, Express.js, Vue.js
- Libraries: LodashSee more on <u>GitHub</u>

#### Galactic Conquest Video Game: Software Engineering (CPS 353)

12/2021

- Third-person alien shooter game, worked on with 3 other team members.
- Languages: C++
- Engine: Unreal Engine 4
- Software: GitHub Desktop and Visio
- See more on <u>GitHub</u>

#### Skills

- Java
- HTML/CSS and PHP
- MySQL
- Python

- Git
- OBS
- Structures / Algorithms
- MS Word

- MS PowerPoint
- MS Excel
- Mathematics
- Critical Thinking

### **Work History**

#### **Disney College Program Attractions**

6/2023 to Present

Disney Parks, Experiences and Products - Lake Buena Vista, FL

- Ensured a safe and reliable experience for guests and team members, demonstrating adaptability and efficiency.
- Operated the Tomorrowland Transit Authority PeopleMover, Space Mountain, and Astro Orbiter, optimizing guest flow with strategic management
- Demonstrated guest interactions for politely resolving frequent guest inquiries, highlighting strong problem-solving skills
- Communicated clear instructions to enhance guests' overall enjoyment of the attraction
- Prioritized and presented safety and entertainment spiels with clarity and enthusiasm
- Executed opening and closing procedures in strict adherence to organizational guidelines

**Audio Visual Technician** 12/2022 to 6/2023

Calvary Chapel Highland - Highland, NY

- Collaborated with information technology department to ensure services and events are able to
  effectively utilize technology in order to enhance the experience of those attending server, virtually or
  in-person
- Work with church staff and leaders to provide audio-visual needs for church services and events

- I am personally responsible for overlaying media with images on multiple projection screens, manually
  operating audio/video systems to correlate with the service leaders' needs, and communicating real
  time with remote attendees via live stream social media
- Work with OBS, Audacity, and EasyWorship on a daily basis

### **Machine Operator Assistant**

4/2023 to 5/2023

Viking Industries Inc. - New Paltz, NY

- Assist the operator in setting up and running high speed manufacturing equipment
- Assist the operator in monitoring and controlling machines
- Assist in adjusting machine parts as needed to ensure proper speed, pressure and amount of material for quality production
- Make sure the work environment remains uncluttered, clean and well-maintained to ensure safety
- Load material into machines
- Place finished goods on pallets, band or wrap for shipment
- Assist with hand finished work when needed

## **Chief Technology Officer**

06/2018 to 06/2022

Rycor HVAC & Refrigeration - New Paltz, NY

- Developed proprietary software to streamline data entry pertaining to the New York State Clean Heat program submissions
- Managed and coordinated all qualified rebates, supplying customers with proper incentives to projects
- Use of Excel to track programs and statuses of all rebates
- Coordinated with New York State Public Commissioner's Office and NYSERDA to implement the processing of clean heat programs in our company and community